# Andy Stanier MChem MSc

andy.stanier@gmail.com www.andystanier.co.uk LinkedIn

Northwich, Cheshire

Andy Stanier has over 6 years' experience as a software developer after having completed a master's degree in computer science with distinction. With a background in chemistry and 15 years' experience in the pharmaceutical industry, Andy is now a skilled and motivated developer using the .NET framework.

After gaining a master's degree in computer science at the University of Hertfordshire, he started a role as a Software Developer for Synectics Solutions where he has been involved in web developing using C#, JavaScript and T-SQL. He has since been involved in multiple projects and worked as a full stack engineer on the websites he has supported.

#### Skills

Andy has used and learned many different languages and techniques and used several different software packages during his time as a developer. These are mostly Microsoft products and frameworks which include C#, TypeScript, HTML, CSS and T-SQL. He has worked with APIs and services, used JavaScript frameworks such as React/Redux, and written scripts in PowerShell and Bash as well as using Git and SVN for source control.

Programming Languages			Software
C#	ASP.NET MVC, Webforms and Core	T-SQL	MS Visual Studio
Git/SVN	TypeScript/JQuery	React/Redux	MS SQL Server Management Studio
HTML	CSS	PowerShell	Visual Studio Code

Andy has also gained many transferable skills during his career.

- Problem Solving overcoming day-to-day issues.
- Research Skills consulting various websites and documents for ideas and solutions.
- Planning what is the best approach to deliver a solution in the shortest time.
- Tenacity working to implement the latest changes to the specification.
- Working to deadlines completing development jobs to a release window.
- Teamwork working in project teams of between 4 and 14 people.
- Independence working unaccompanied on sub-projects.

# **Work History**

#### Oct 2016 - Present

# Software Developer at Synectics Solutions, Stoke-On-Trent

Software developer for internal and client facing websites. Using ASP.NET MVC framework combined with C#, T-SQL, JavaScript, TypeScript, React, Razor, HTML, and CSS to maintain websites for clients including the UK Government, for which he is Security Cleared, many large banking and financial organisations and clients within the automotive industry.

# Day to day tasks include:

- Maintenance of existing code to address client-found bugs.
- Introduction of new features into the existing website, often doing the database and backend logic as well as the frontend user interface.
- New project websites or conversion of webforms pages to MVC.
- Writing of Unit tests.
- Use of JIRA to track and record progress.
- GIT for source control.

## Aug 2015 - Sept 2016

### Distance Learning Master's Student in Computer Science, University of Hertfordshire

See Education section for more details.

## May 2014 - Aug 2015

# Synthetic Chemist at Molplex Pharmaceuticals, Alderley Park

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Molplex was a small biochemical start-up, whose aim was to use Artificial Intelligence to design new drugs for orphan diseases.

#### Dec 2013 - May 2014

# Looking for work - Job searching, CV writing and IT courses.

During this period, Andy attended Jobcentre run courses in CV writing, went to IT courses and applied for jobs in the pharmaceutical industry.

#### Jan 2011 - Dec 2013

# Synthetic Organic Chemist for CK Science at Eisai, Hatfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department. Designed and synthesised libraries of compounds for screening.

#### Aug 2008 - Jan 2011

#### Medicinal Chemist at AstraZeneca, Charnwood, Loughborough

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the chemistry department.

#### July 2001 - Aug 2008

# Synthetic Chemist at AstraZeneca, Alderley Park, Macclesfield

This job ended in redundancy due to closure of the research area.

#### Education

# Computer Science at University of Hertfordshire, UK - Distinction.

A distance learning Master's degree in computer science, studying the following:

- **Programming and Program Design** Learning **Java** language and Object-Oriented Programming techniques. Assessment by exams and coursework; the final piece was a desktop program, written from scratch to a provided specification.
- Web Scripting and Application Development Learning about server-side website design using ASP.NET Webforms, C# and SQL. Created a website of user generated content.
- **Contemporary Practices in Information Technology** The ethics of information technology, assessed by researching and writing essays.
- Mobile Standards, Interfaces and Applications Using JavaScript, JSON and jQuery Mobile to generate a mobile website.
- **Secure Systems Programming** Exploring security problems with the **C** programming language and how to avoid them, plus learning about DDOS, BotNets, Worms and Viruses.
- Software Development Tools and Methods Ways to develop software, UML, XML, secure systems development. Assessment by essay and coursework drawing UML diagrams.
- Final Project in Computer Science A piece of research and practical work about Electronic Voting Systems, creating a desktop Java application and an HTML5 website for vote verification. Version control was handled by Git software.

#### Chemistry at University of York, UK

Chemistry with a Year in Industry, MChem with First Class Honours.

Three years of study and practical labs, coursework and exams. A fourth year was spent working in an industrial setting as a synthetic chemist in a drug discovery research department. Learning on the job and completing a written report and exams.

# A Levels at Tytherington High School, Macclesfield

Four 'A' Levels in Mathematics (A), Chemistry (A), Physics (B) and General Studies (A).

This CV is also available at www.andystanier.co.uk.